Sunnyvale, CA (408) 320-8343 rodwoodman.com

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Front-End Focused Full Stack Developer

Versatile and thorough Web applications developer who loves building dashboards that satisfy users. Embraces subjectivity in front-end data presentation with a grounding in full stack development experience. Balances systems thinking with attention-to-detail to solve whole-product challenges. Open collaborator driven to continually improve UX and simplify design complexity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- <u>Code</u>: HTML, CSS, SASS, ExtJS, Angular, React, Highcharts, Python, Golang, MongoDB.
- <u>Tools</u>: REST APIs, VSC, Git, Bitbucket, vim, Sublime Text 2, Photoshop, Balsamiq, Omnigraffle.
- Methods: OOP, Continuous Integration, SPA, wikis, UX, user-centered design (UCD), wireframes.
- <u>Soft skills</u>: analytical, user-focused, communicative, collaborative, transparent, iterative.
- Core values: transparency, growth, perspective.

SAMPLE WEB APPS

UI Developer - GitHub @roderickwoodman

2019 – present

- Daily development of my personal apps: Boardgameinator, ComparingStocks, TrailProfiler.
- Interactive dashboards that generate comparative insights on the everydata of my life.
- HTML, CSS, JS, React, Vue, GitHub Pages
- Boardgameinator: Board game comparisons; React, Bootstrap, BoardGameGeek.com API;
- <u>ComparingStocks</u>: Meaningful stock allocation data; React, Alpha Vantage API;
- <u>TrailProfiler</u>: Charts together GPX and JPG files; Vue, ChartistJS, Bootstrap;

EXPERIENCE

ARUBA NETWORKS, Santa Clara, CA

2016 - 2020

1,800-person mobile-first networking company owned by Hewlett Packard Enterprise Company.

Senior Applications Engineer - Support Portal for Aruba Central Guest

- Jointly responsible on a team of 6 for a supportability interface to a cloud-native NMS application.
- Owned a dashboard of front-end (Angular, Bootstrap) and back-end (Python, REST) code.
- Supported operations with health monitoring (AWS CloudWatch, Elasticsearch, Kibana).
- Developed under continuous integration (Git, Bitbucket, JIRA, Docker, K8S, Jenkins, TerraForm).
- Added a RadSec capture UI, as well as integrated Twilio and SendGrid 3rd party APIs.
- Documented and presented the ecosystem architecture (Confluence, Zoom, Gliffy).

Senior Applications Engineer - Config Sync tool for ClearPass

- Solely responsible for a new tool to audit and sync the configs of 100+ Aruba ClearPass clusters.
- Owned a dashboard of front-end (ExtJS, SASS) and back-end (Golang, REST) code in SVN.
- Designed and built the entire UI and internal APIs from informal product requirements using UCD.
- Communicated across timezones with remote product manager and remote customer agent.
- Released the major functionality of scheduling, reporting, filtering, exporting, backup and restore.
- Proposed to management a significant design simplification of the legacy ClearPass policy UI.

11-person startup that provided terrestrial, wireless Internet to cruise ships near port.

NMS Engineer - True Air NMS

- Jointly responsible on a team of 2 for the cloud-native Network Management System (NMS) product.
- Owned a dashboard of front-end (HighCharts, Bootstrap) and back-end (Python, Flask, MongoDB).
- Redesigned the UI for better network insights from the collected telemetry data.
- Sped up the pace code releases to be every 2-3 weeks (Git, Bitbucket, JIRA, Jenkins).
- Collaborated with firmware engineers to integrate new, 3rd party endpoint hardware (csh).
- Designed and implemented a compression algorithm that reduced telemetry file size by 84%.

CISCO SYSTEMS, San Jose, CA

2005 - 2014

A 65,000-person networking company with \$35B in annual sales.

Software Developer - Catalyst 6K and Nexus 6K

- Jointly responsible on a team of 10+ for a diagnostic firmware test suite. Two-week sprints.
- Designed and implemented packet transfer tests and system-level packet stress tests (C, Linux).
- Extended system tests to multiple platforms.
- Applied extensive codebase knowledge to improve test module APIs.
- Created single-page debug block diagram of routing logic from 900 pages of specifications.
- Presented a multi-session codebase overview to China team as part of ownership transfer.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Master of Science in Computer Engineering Santa Clara University, Santa Clara, CA

Bachelor of Science in Electronic Engineering Cal Poly State University, San Luis Obispo, CA

MEAN Stack Blackbelt Coding Dojo, San Jose, CA

Web Design Certificate
UCSC Extension Silicon Valley, Santa Clara, CA